good evening ladies and gentlemen a very
warm welcome to icic Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited Q3 and 9
months fy23 earnings conference call
from the Senior Management we have with
us today Mr Marga
mdn CEO of the company
Mr gopal balachandran CFO and cro
Mr Sanjeev mantri executive director
executive director
please note that any statements or
comments are made in today's call they
that may look like forward-looking
statements are based on information
presently available to the management
and do not constitute an indication of
any future performance as future
involves risk and uncertainties which
could cause results to differ materially
from the current views being expressed
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the lesson only mode and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during the conference call please signal
an operator by pressing star then read
on your Touchstone phone
thank you and over to yourself
as always I will give you a brief
overview of the industry Trends and
developments that we've witnessed in the
past few months post this us here for Mr
gopal college and then we'll share the
financial performance of the company for
a quarter and nine months ended December
31 2022.
during the quarter the Indian economy
was largely driven by domestic
consumption with activity across the
industry and services sectors in
extension mode
credit growth has been showing
double-digit growth since April 2020
supported by both retail and wholesale
lending however the synchronized
tightening of policy raised by global
central banks has been slowing down
Global demand and international trade
Global slowdown has been putting
pressure on the current account and can
adversely impact domestic growth going
going forward
for the quarter as for data published by
CM the new vehicle sales continue to
deliver strong growth year on year for
Private Car segments with continued
momentum in the underlying Insurance
demand
the commercial vehicle segment growth
was supported by Rover's growth and end
user in Industries such as in drug
infrastructure and e-commerce while the
two wheeler segment grew on a smaller
base however in volume terms the segment
continues to remain below three pandemic
levels
health insurance continue to drive the
overall industry course
the commercial lines with his growth in
line with the current market environment
we remain optimistic that the insurance
industry will continue to grow given the
low penetration favorable regulatory
changes and positive consumer sentiment
taking the performance the GI industry
delivered a gdpi growth of 16.2 percent
for nine months a 52x3 excluding crop
the growth of 17.5 for the same period
at the same time the underwriting
performance remained poor with a
combined ratio of the industry at 116.6
percent
as on half year 2023. for motor business
combined ratio for the industry was
123.5 percent for half year 2023 as
compared to 110.4 for half year 2022 as
for public disclosures
the alternating current in The Current
financial year has introduced various
reforms speaking to expand the market
and increase the penetration of
insurance products towards its mission
of insurance for for all by query 47.
during the quarter there and the
authority mandated kyc requirements
which affected from January March 2023
modified the increase in number of tires
from three to nine in case of
Corporations for each category of
insurance
notified regulatory sandbox regulations
eliminated in the time limit to facility
innovation in products for Solutions and
to increase the experimental period up
to 36 months
for children working committee to police
effective pregnancy framework Force the
demodification of existing tariff
earnings Under Fire engineering and
motor OD
D so for long-term motor insurance
products covering motorod and motor TV
and long-term fire Insurance products
the authorities also issued registration
of insurance company regulations
simplifying persons of registration for
insurance companies to promote ease of
building business
we believe that these changes will be
disrupted in the short term but we'll
have a positive effect on the insurance
direct pressure over the long term
moving to business impact for us during
the quarter the company grew by 16.9 as
compared to the industry growth of 18.1
excluding crop the company grew by 17.1
coming to the growth 40 segments during
the quarters in motor OD because the
remote of the growth even neutral at 4.7
the comparative intensity continuous and
the motor will be side especially on the
private car segment we continue to focus
on profitable sub segments using
historical granular data and rebalance
our portfolio resulting in CV mix at
22.2 percent for nine months of fl0
the fastest growing segment for the
industry during the quarter we grew at
47.9 which was significantly higher than
the industry growth of 24.9 as a result
of a continued investment in health and
Retail Health distribution we have
outgrown the industry in Standalone
players with the growth of 24.2 percent
this was given by business source
through Eagle health agency vertical
which grew up which grew up 40.1 percent
I would also like to share that our
One-Stop solution for all insurance and
wellness needs I'll take care of as our
past 3.7 million user download till date
the incremental download for the quarter
was
0.9 million I'll take care I have
contributed to 33 47.9 million to the
gbpi of Q3 fi 23.
distribution grew by 44.2 percent
post pandemic the recovery and credit
growth along with increase in wallet
share and distribution Partners acquired
through the demotion has in the creek
figure drivers
our business source through our digital
monitoring we were Google 2820
overall our digital Focus has enabled us
to increase our digital revenues to 2.62
billion rupees which are consequent
accounts for 4.8 percent of our overall
GDP gbpa for this quarter this excludes
revenues from I'll take care I have
mentioned earlier
as far as the commercial lines are
concerned we experience robust growth
driven by growth of 25.2 percent in the
atomic segment
we remain on track and our focus on
growth leavers such as Innovation
digital advancements new products
strengthening distribution engine
rationalizing costs while scaling up our
preferred lines of business
I will now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers so that we
can be concluded with co-workers
thanks Mother friend good evening to
each one of you I will now give you a
brief overview on the financial
performance of the company for quarter
three and nine months of fy23 we have
uploaded the results presentation on our
website you can access it as we walk you
through the performance numbers
the GDP of the company was rupees 160.48
billion in nine months at 523 as against
rupees 1.133.11 billion in nine months
at 522 the growth of 20.6 which was
higher than the industry growth of 16.2
percent
excluding crop gdpi growth of the
company was at 19.9 which was higher
than the industry growth of 17.5 percent
in nine months and 523
gdpa was at 54.93 billion rupees in
quarter three fi 23.
the growth of 16.9 percent as against
industry growth of 18.1 percent
excluding crop GDP growth of the company
was at 17.1 percent which was higher
than the district growth of 16.6 percent
in quarter 3 and 523
our GDP growth was primarily driven by
growth in the preferred segments the
overall GDP of our Property and Casualty
segment grew by 17.8 percent at rupees
46.35 billion in nine months at 523 as
against rupees 39.34 billion in nine
months by 22. on the retail side of the
business GDP of the motor segment was at
rupees 64 billion in nine months fy23
apps against 58.15 billion in 9 months
of 522 registering a growth of 10.1
percent
our agents including point of sale or
POS count was at one lakh six thousand
one one nine as on December 31 2022
from one lakh 636 as on September 30
2022 the advanced premium was rupees
32.79 billion as at December 31 22 as
against rupees 34.34 billion as at
September 30 22. resultantly combined
ratio was
104.6 percent in 99523 as against
hundred and eleven percent in nine
months at 522
combined ratio was 104.4 percent in
quarter three fi 23 asking 104.5 in
quarter three fy22 our investment assets
Rose to 414.51 billion as at December
from 400.96 billion as at September 30
2022 our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 4.16 times
as at December 31 2022 as against 4.08
times as at September 30 2022.
investment income was at rupees 21.6
billion in 9 months at 523 as against
rupees 22.95 billion in 9 months f522.
on a quarterly basis investment income
increased to rupees 7.66 billion in 43
fy23 as against rupee 6.9 billion in 43
fy22
our capital gains net of impairment on
Equity investment assets should at
rupees 2.94 billion and 9 months f523 as
compared to rupees 6.01 billion in 9
months f522
capital gains in quarter three f523 was
at rupees 1.52 billion as compared to
rupees 1.31 billion in quarter three
fy22
our profit before tax grew by 21 at 15.4
billion rupees in 9 months and 523
that's against 12.73 billion rupees in
nine months of the previous year
whereas profit before tax grew by 10.5
percent at rupees 4.65 billion in
quarter three fi23 as against rupees
4.21 billion in quarter three f522
consequently profit after tax grew by
34.8 percent at rupees 12.92 billion in
nine months fi 23 has against rupees
9.59 billion nine months up by 22.
whereas profit approved by 11 percent
at rupees 3.53 billion in 43 f523 from
rupees 3.18 billion in quarter three fi
22. fact includes reversal of tax
division of rupees 1.28 billion in
Quarter Two at 523 excluding this gross
impact was 21.4 percent for 9 months
f523 return on average Equity was 18.1
percent in nine months f523 as against
fifteen point one percent in nine months
up by 22. the return on average equity
for quarter three fi 23 was at 14.3
percent
at the age 14.6 in quarter three fi 22.
solvency ratio was at 2.45 times as a
December 31 2022
or seven times as at September 30 22
be higher than the regulatory minimum of
1.5 times as I conclude I would like to
reiterate we continue to stay focused on
driving profitable growth sustainable
value creation and safeguarding interest
of policyholders at all times
I would like to thank you for attending
this earnings call and we would be happy
to take any questions that you may have
thank you
thank you very much
we will now begin the question and
answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on the Touchstone
telephone
if you wish to withdraw yourself from
the question queue you may press star
and two
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles
reminder to the participants anyone who
wishes to ask a question may press star
and one
the first question is from the line of
swalla Mukherjee from bnk Securities
please go ahead
thank you for the opportunity and
congrats for the numbers and segment
number seems to be coming out very
nicely so just wanted to understand on
that segment in a little bit more detail
you have
shared that way we will see the segment
in detail has grown by 40 percent
the audio is not clear from your line
please use the handset mode yeah okay
just give me a moment
here is this better
yes it's better yes okay okay so so uh
on the retail Health you will see uh
side if you could give some color on
what would be sharing the mix and uh how
do you anticipate this to be growing uh
going ahead that would be very helpful
because that growth of 40 percent must
have come on a slightly smaller base so
will that growth rate fasting or how
will it stand out that is the first
question that I have second is uh on the
motor PP loss ratio so this quarter the
number is very very strong so how should
we think about that particularly that
you know this quarter I am seeing that
there has been some amount of themes in
the gdpa mix between two wheeler and CV
so is that also a quarterly kind of a
thing which should reverse because I
thought that you wanted to keep CV at
around 24 25
so broadly yeah these are my questions
so maybe the specifically the people ask
Google to answer but to answer your
first question on uh
on the uh in the retail Health business
as we've been saying when you uh invest
in a in the scale that we are doing uh
you know relative to our current size it
takes time for people to come in
stabilize uh you know higher agents or
patients to become active and then
productive it takes some time so we've
been saying it will start building up
uh maybe you know three to six months uh
from the time that we started talking
about it so this quarter is the first
quarter where we are beginning to see
the real impact of the investment that
we are making
but this is still uh you know early days
we are very confident that this growth
number for the retail health agency
channel will scale from going ahead
overall health growth will be given by
multiple other factors you will have to
look at what happens when the bank
issuesite because if you look at a group
health number that's also growing quite
fast compared to the industry that's
driven by two reasons one the bank
Assurance channels that we've talked
about you know both in terms of what
came through through these the
acquisition as also in terms of our
existing Partners they are going uh
really well uh
so right now we are increasing pricing
we are still winning accounts because I
think the market is finally uh
stabilizing in terms of sizing so that
goes will uh come through as long as the
price is to our satisfaction so that's
to give you a world perspective on help
but specific if your question is on
retail health agency growth can be
sustain 40 then we believe we can
okay okay so any any color on the mix
how much would be retail health agency
now in your overall retail
some ballpark number would be
fine
so I think relatively I think it's kind
of going well uh if you look at our
overall
uh within that I think the agency
vertical has kind of grown at about 40
percent
uh so hence I think uh as Vargo
mentioned one of the other things that
we have been talking to the market is to
try and sustain whether on retail Health
Indemnity can we sustainable growth
numbers which is faster than not just
the industry but even the Standalone
Health companies
but at least for the last four months in
September onwards I think we have been
able to kind of demonstrate that I think
the key will be to sustain it as we kind
of look forward but really we are kind
of optimistic and we are continuing to
make those investments in uh
in the retail Health distribution
franchise
to your second
for a thought process is concerned at
least on the selection of business weeks
within motor there is no change in
thought process which is to say that
while the market continues to remain
competitive at least on certain segments
of private car for sure and therefore we
continue to take a calibrated position
wherever we see opportunities whether
it's on two wheeler or CV I think
obviously we have been writing those
profitable segments as what we indicated
as a part of our opening remarks in the
process is what we had indicated that
possibly our mix of commercial vehicles
could stay a range bound within let's
say around that 24 25 threshold enough
water that number going down to let's
say 22 percent mix I think obviously
it's a function of what kind of uh
business makes that one is able to
Source in a particular quarter and given
the fact that Q3 generally is a seasonal
quarter when it comes to let's say a
writing of risks between Private Car two
wheelers and commercial vehicles so in
some other thought process is concerned
I think so far as the year end mix is
concerned we should get to see the CV
around that range of uh 23 24 kind of
levels is what one would say so this is
the pH if water where there are a lot of
tested demand for private current two
wheeler so those numbers get delivered
in this quarter that's the reason why
the mix is relatively smaller for CVS
nothing else yeah and your other point
on the TP loss issues
again that's what we keep saying uh I
mean you have to obviously look at uh
loss ratios again not between quarters
obviously you have to look at it
moreover longer longer periods uh
ideally at a year today year end basis
is the best way to kind of look at the
TP loss issues because in some quarters
you will obviously see the effect of
some of the uh some of the let's say
positions that we have taken from a
reserving perspective that we would
start to see it getting played out and
so far as actual launch development
experiences are concerned so and since
in that particular quarter you may
possibly see some kind of a release of
reserves that would have kind of been
given effect too and corresponding to
that is what you get to see the
outcoming so far as the TP loss ratio
numbers are concerned but otherwise in
so far it's reserving philosophy is
concerned I don't think we have there is
any change in the reserving philosophy
uh it kind of pretty much Remains the
Same uh and hence you should look at
more the TP loss ratios over not just on
a quarter on quarter basis but look at
it moreover longer periods of
development
you know think about it going ahead save
for the next three four quarters how it
will plan out because it continues to
remain elevated close to around 30
percent
Mark which is what we had indicated uh
that's what we have been kind of talking
through uh what essentially happens is
particularly when you are continuing
with your investments in various areas
of opportunities that we have spoken
about in terms of long-term growth
potential
whether it is with respect to the
opportunity that we see on the digital
side or even for the matter of fact the
continued investment that we are making
on building the retail Health
distribution franchise where it's not
just a one-off addition to Manpower that
we did last year that's a continuing one
even as we speak in the current period
as well now all of this is something
we have been explaining in our earlier
calls will entail in a printing of
the benefit of revenues is obviously
something that will get paid out over a
period of time now as I mentioned in
response to the earlier one clearly we
are seeing early signs of some of those
Investments getting played out in terms
of our growth percentages reflecting
those Investments right hand
given the fact that it is a continuing
one we will obviously get to see the
expense ratio stay at the current levels
at where we are kind of largely
operating at
having said that we will obviously
Monitor and come back to the market and
give an update in terms of how those
Investments are playing out in each of
the areas
so that's something that will be a
continuing one uh obviously Revenue will
catch up your other point on let's say
some of the Investments between capex
and Optics I think that's something that
is again an ongoing one
uh as we have been talking through we do
undertake various transformational
projects which will keep the
organization future ready uh in terms of
our ability to deliver products and
services to the market and hence that
Excel you will obviously see continuing
Investments whether it is on capitals or
whether it is for the matter of fact any
operating expenses so the only aspect
that I will add
is uh for Q4 or online with what we have
been again talking about we have been
able to successfully complete the
technology migration
which we had kind of indicated that we
will complete it by quarter three of
this year that's pretty much kind of
done and as to that extent the benefit
of whatever amount of synergies that we
were expected to realize out of those
technology expense is something that we
will start to see from Q4 onwards
yes one more comment to add
so as we shared with you after we moved
our entire technology task to the cloud
right so all our applications are Cloud
so that's the call that is taken not
from a cafe Services office perspective
because all of the you know part of the
capacity in future it will be converted
into operate so that's the call that
we've taken in the interest of business
from a longer term perspective it gives
us more agility more you know
electricity so you know more scalability
so all of that factors go in our
decision uh from a longer term
perspective rather than looking at
whether you want to keep that experience
on-prem and kind of advertise cost over
period and you know look at Capital
versus Optics to manage your financials
questions
ladies and gentlemen in order to ensure
that the management is able to address
questions from all participants in the
conference please limit your questions
to two per participant should you have a
follow-up question we would request you
to rejoin the question to you the next
question is from The Lion of Avinash
from MK Global Financial Services please
go ahead
yeah hi good evening a couple of
questions and both looking at nine
months data just to sort of a clear out
the noise of the water to water uh
firstly I mean now the combined ratio at
around say 100 405 that is where you
have indicated now because of this uh
you know uh investment side volatility
and if I were to remove the tax refund
or this 100 405 combined is leading to a
more of a sixteen percent kind of Roe
now is that where I mean you are
comfortable because I mean uh if the
investment Fields continue to be at this
level probably this combined ratio means
that uh the Roe is at 16 or percent
level so are you comfortable with uh
this thing I mean you can argue that I
mean obviously where industry is a
secretary you are much better but I mean
of course you don't have the advantage
of not being listed you are listed
companies of course you are monitor on
parameters so that question on sort of
your you know balancing your command is
your growth and profitability that
number one and number two again I if I
look at motor as a combined portfolio
you know uh what I see uh there is like
uh on a year on your basis your loss if
you are more or less fine I mean that's
100 Point movement uh but if I just go
and uh sort of delve down into
underwriting results it suggests that I
mean uh overall or there's a kind of a
material increase on the Optics sizing
motor so if you can just help uh
understand what is or is the Opex or
that is driving uh perhaps that are you
know a higher underwriting losses or on
a nine months basis
thank you so let me take the first one
and I'll ask gopal to the breakdown of
uh you know where there is
on the first as we've articulated uh you
know since the time that we uh
transaction he has said that we
developing energy benefits that we were
we had assumed but in reality we have
seen highest energy benefits we felt
that it was appropriate from a long-term
perspective to invest that for uh for
growth and that is what we did I mean it
was really a capital allocation call of
looking at the longer term versus some
short-term efficiency
we also said that in the first couple of
years maybe the combination will be
elevated by our Endeavor will always be
two reduce it will get closer to maybe
102 in a couple of years
So to that extent our uh our view or our
our Outlook hasn't changed
if that happens obviously our Ro is
actually indicated in the past will be
in the high things now you can calculate
the array for yourself it will probably
be 160 if it if we achieve the objective
that we set for ourselves it is also a
fact that you know
you know uh pricing resolution on the
motor would be size to the extent that
we have experienced in the last six
months that has had uh you know some
impact on us this year but what we're
seeing is that finally we are seeing
some calibration some moderation we have
seen some early signs of improvement and
if that happens uh you know that will
help us in achieving the objective that
we've talked about so hopefully you know
just to explain your answer your
question uh it is not about being
complement where we are this is really a
short-term journey to achieve something
which is more valuable for the longer
term objective in the longer term is
continues to be improving combined and
improving our ways
and your second point on the motor uh
underwriting experience Avinash
I think it's a function of two things
one is uh obviously you will have to
look at it in the context of what kind
of growth are we exhibiting uh so
relative to let's say the market yes you
would have seen clearly on motor in the
aggregate we have kind of underperformed
which is a conscious call that we're
kind of taking uh in order to kind of
stay focused on uh the selecting
portfolios which is from a profitability
perspective
uh and to that action obviously there is
a denominator effect that tends to play
out when it comes to the expensive
issues
and two uh given the fact that at the
end of the day there is obviously a set
of expenses that you can either
ID with a particular segment but equally
there are large expenses which are which
are of let's say of a fixed nature which
typically gets allocated between various
uh product line
and therefore to that extent that will
also be a function of let's say what
outcome that you see and so far as the
overall expense ratios for a particular
segment is concerned which is why uh
instead of maybe specifically looking at
individual lines of businesses uh from
an expense ratio standpoint it is rather
better to look at the overall expense
ratios for the company as a whole which
if you look at it at least on a whether
you look at it on a nine month to nine
month basis uh I mean or which let's say
even for the matter of fact when you
look at those numbers on a quarter on
quarter basis the the expense ratios
have kind of largely stayed around the
threshold of around 29.5 to around which
is 30 thereabout uh so hence as growth
gets revived particularly in the context
of motor and the fact that we have kind
of indicated the market at this point of
time is obviously competitive which is
why as a part of the opening remarks we
also specifically put out
for motor the industry combined ratios
continue to stay elevated at almost
about 124 percent
and hence once we start to see as what
Vargo also mentioned some bit of evening
easing is what we have seen but once we
start seeing the cycle completely
turning back we will be obviously able
to get the growth back and therefore to
that extent you will also see maybe the
expense ratios getting allocated to that
segment reflecting better numbers
foreign
so that came in at about 1.88 for this
quarter and uh if we sort of plot your
yields versus The Five-Year GSA killed
performance uh this your years have sort
of ranged between 1.7 to 2 on quarterly
basis since even during FY 2021 when the
gcules were at its lowest in the recent
past right so I'm trying to understand
where are we missing on the yields bit
if you can help me understand that
because my main question is that we
would be we were expecting this to be uh
higher than what it has turned out to be
first is on that second is on the uh
crop book so for the nine month period
the loss ratio is sort of inched up to
90 now last time you had mentioned that
you've written a big chunk of this
business with Maharashtra government
which has some Gap loss program at 80 80
110 or something like that so uh how is
the performance of that book and whether
this inching up of the loss ratio is
from the bharti aksa book so just trying
to understand where the higher loss
ratio is coming from and on third is on
retail Health uh the last you had
mentioned that you guys have hired a
thousand uh retail Health sales managers
and each one of them will go out and
onboard more agents Etc so if you can
give us an update on whether all those
thousand onboarding is finished are we
hiring more sales manager and
um how is that process going
basis that reflects roughly about 7.52
which given the current interest regime
is uh we would think is pretty good in
terms of uh you know realizing yield on
the portfolio uh on the second one uh in
terms of uh on the crop so uh our entire
crop book yesterday
book there is no change in terms of what
we are dealing with the with the book
performance in Q2 which is last quarter
based on actual realization of the
uh experience we had some religions we
of course that you know we do is that
till we get the complete results we tend
to reserve conservatively and then once
we actually get the final data then we
release if at all there's a scope for
release we will do that so this quarter
will Reserve as our as our practice in a
conservative manner our belief is on the
underlying voice is what we get to see
the Khalid uh you know the Ravi losses
are well within our comfort level and
retail health agency managers that we
kind of spoken of to be hired that's
pretty much kind of done and as I said
this is the continuing one it's not that
it's a one-off Investments that we
wanted to do in that we spoke of it
since Quarter Two of last year so that's
a continuing one and that's and as I had
indicated obviously early signs of uh
early signs have been getting played out
is what I spoke about since September
onwards we are getting to see month on
month Traction in us really exhibiting
also for months related you to even the
Standalone Health companies
and the key will be for us to kind of
sustain this momentum as we kind of
build up this distribution for the end
of the day as we have kind of also
integrated in the past the market share
on details for us is still at sub three
percent it's about 2.9 to three percent
in that range so there is clearly an
opportunity for us to kind of stay
invested and possibly try and increase
market share
sure just one clarification so the
Maharashtra crop book was also a part of
the bharti bharti book or I thought that
was a new new uh uh contract that you
guys have entered into
you're right
but the cop business came with party
access
thank you Miss Shivani may we request
that you return to the question thank
you for follow-up questions
next question is from the line of hitesh
gulati from high tongue please go ahead
thank you for giving me an opportunity
so firstly I wanted to understand one
agency in retail Health how many agents
would have been added so for instance if
we have 1000 new sales force uh how many
agents would be active in health so I
think in the past we had about 6 000
agents selling health so what would that
number be right now
exactly
we'll just give you a number which come
back to you with the number it shows it
and so the second question I had was uh
so these benefit policies I assume other
than the ijst banks the other
Partnerships that we have here doing uh
attachment products with them and these
policies generally tend to be quite
profitable so is that this scenario and
should we expect that uh combined ratio
in this segment will be good with all
these distribution Partnerships that we
are working on
so absolutely it is I think uh if you
recollect uh while the mix currently on
health for us is cured more in terms of
Indemnity as compared to benefit but if
you look at historically the mix was
actually the opposite where we had a
relatively large proportion of Health
premium contributed more by the benefit
uh product and relatively at that point
of time we were building up the
indemnity franchise for the last couple
of years on the benefit segment because
of Market constraints in terms of credit
disposals being significantly lower and
also what we have explained in terms of
the decision that one of our Bank
distribution partner at taken so all of
that is behind us which is why now as we
speak the create dispersals is back and
this segment is obviously a profitable
one and that's really and yes you are
right it's uh it's something that will
kind of uh contribute to our
underwriting outcomes and in general the
product segment is positive
that shows just one last thing said
investment income on a QQ basis is lower
but I think on capital gains it's not
materially different can you just guide
on that
so there is no specific consideration
behind jakitesh because uh I think uh
between quarters uh in so far as capital
gain numbers are concerned that could
also kind of vary between periods to
periods but otherwise it is pure as we
have always indicated in general when
you look at the breakup of our overall
investment income roughly about
three-fourth of that investment income
tends to be through invest through
accruals and roughly about one-fourth
happens to capital gains now it's quite
possible that in some quarter you have a
capital gain number which is precisely
higher in mix but otherwise between
quarters there is no specific change in
the underlying investment thought
process in general I think obviously we
are changing this opportunity of higher
interest rates which which obviously
kind of offers well in so far as higher
accruals are concerns Finance to that
extent is what you get to see the income
between quarter to quarter more as an
outcome as compared to anything that is
specifically contributing to it
thank you Mr gulati may I request that
you return to the question thank you for
follow-up questions the next question is
from the line of prayers chain from
motilal as well please go ahead
uh yeah hi uh just a couple of questions
on my side uh for three uh gopal if you
could mention uh how do we think about
the unexpired risk weather for the four
years of fi 23 now that you have gone
into nine months and I I understand that
it depends on what kind of growth we see
in the in the remainder in fourth
quarter but assuming a ballpark growth
what we've seen around 15 percent do we
see uh you know the entity
growth to be better going ahead that is
one secondly uh so from a reserve the
insult sorry in the motor segment uh I
would like your views as to when do we
really see growth coming strongly in the
end for you guys you know uh what would
be the point or what are the factors
that can really drive this growth uh
back to a high you know like in line
with the industries are even better than
the industry and in the past you've been
alluding to the fact that past few
quarters that the motor will be pricing
has become more or less you know is
getting some cognizance and is getting
better but we don't see that in the
numbers yet so uh any further thoughts
there that could be helpful
there's a price on the first one
honestly what is
what is when it comes to unexpected
preserve it's purely a function of
what kind of business mix that you write
and the earnings is purely a function of
the contract term for which let's say
the policies are issued and hence to
that extent like for example if
last part of
we have a one-year duration essential
election the earnings will typically
kind of get uh earned over the contract
period uh so so hence to that extent uh
given the fact that let's say for
example this particular year we have
seen let's say the growth being
relatively better than what we had seen
let's say in the past two periods which
is why you get to see in whichever
period you are writing the higher
Quantum of business
to that extent for the period at which
you're ending up reporting numbers you
end up carrying a higher amount of
unexpected results which will obviously
get released in the future periods
the outcome will be to look at more
because corresponding to that you would
also have let's say the loss experience
getting uh played out as well yeah so
rather it is better to look at more
either the loss ratio numbers for the
company as a whole or more importantly I
think combined issues will be far more a
better reflection rather than just
looking at uh anything on a standalone
basis because it has got multiple
factors as you rightly mentioned in
terms of mix of business at what point
of time have you kind of writing those
risks and so on and so forth so hence
better way to kind of look at this more
let's say the law Solutions and the
combined ratios so that's in response to
the first one uh so your second point on
when do we see let's say our changing
stance I think obviously we have this is
not the first time that we have been
kind of taking a calibrated call with
with respect to going a little slow in
writing certain segments of business now
that's the reason why just to kind of
repeat what we had put out as a part of
the introductory
opening remarks is what you get just an
outcome for the overall Market with
respect to the motor combined issues
completely you see this is public
information so which is why I mean the
industry as a whole is operating at a
company 24 right obviously it does not
make viable sense for us to kind of
significantly go after that segment
which is going to exhibit a very adverse
underwriting Outsource that's the reason
why we have been taking calibrated calls
in the segments where we think the
competitive intensity is far more
elevated but our sense is given that now
we are seeing maybe continued quarters
of combined ratio staying eliminated for
the market we don't think this can
something that can continue to sustain
for maybe a further longer period of
time already we are seeing which is what
Varga also mentioned uh we are clearly
seeing signs of some of the players in
the market starting to become far more
rational when it comes to underwriting
this particular segment so our services
we will obviously watch out for the
development over the next couple of
quarters
and then but at least in so far as our
investments is concerned I think we're
pretty much staying on course in the
sense that we are kind of expanding
investments in expanding distribution
even on the motor side whether it comes
to working with oems in terms of the
number of dealers whom we have access to
or for the matter of fact even with the
number of agents that we are working
with which is what you would have seen
for the company as a whole again the
aggregate number of countries
so we are continuing to make those
investments in writing those businesses
as and when we see the opportunity turn
up we are kind of better place to ride
this particular segment of business
thank you Mr Jane May request not to
return to the question queue for
follow-up questions
the next question is from the line of
sanket Goda from spark Capital please go
ahead
uh thank you for the opportunity uh can
you give me the lottery for breakdown
for retail health benefit-based health
and Group Health and Pa is possible but
this is to understand how it is turning
out given given the last part of the
business will be new in nature this this
wanted to understand whether it is it is
it is substantially below 60 or 65
especially in case only to indemnity
it doesn't get uh I think I'm just
giving you right now quarter three
numbers
uh quarter three loss ratios for the
corporate health book which is a ghi
portfolio that number is 98.9 and in so
far as the retail Indemnity book is
concerned that number is instead of 68
okay
I'm just really uh still asking because
you got 68 uh is is which means it might
be a total of 30 percent Roe products
which means you are saving your product
which will drop down the entire Roe of
the company
consider just wanted on this time the 68
is like a sustainable number what you
look to the kind of growth you are
delivering or it could come down in your
view
so we can get there a couple of factors
one is the mix of new versus old so our
new mix is increasing as we are you know
the of the fresh business is increasing
but that uh that entity of that book
hasn't thrown in as much so as that
happens we lost ratio is expected to
come down a bit second is we are also
looking at repricing the reinsurance
the the renewal book which is something
that you will do um in this quarter
itself so overall we expect the last
ratio to further come down got it and in
health it has been a phenomenal year for
us this year at least for nine months so
it's author of the entire Health if I
look the pa uh benefit-based health and
Group Health are driven by some some
kind of a factors which are not
repeatable in nature like like creative
growth being very strong and and Group
Health Rising being better so so I mean
I just wanted to check whether the group
health pricing you have already seen a
correction and and if on a higher base
the credit growth slows down then the
highly profitable products like benefit
based and clear might contribute lower
in the next year uh so so uh this just
wanted to know uh retail Indemnity as
you highlighted might might do well
because of the English films you have
made but but the kind of group what you
have reported health and PA 40 plus and
plus uh in in in overall so many months
what likely number you expect it to
moderate in instead of 24.
we used to have roughly 75 of our
business in the hell coming from the
vacation you know the retail benefit
structure so uh this year it looks like
suddenly it's increased because of the
low base of the last two years uh going
ahead against the credit go to uh I mean
particularly for let's say uh retail for
a you know retail credit go to come down
significantly
um you know that's a problem if it comes
on 60 25 some other uh you know
macroeconomic reasons of course it will
come down in terms of but we believe
that you know We Are One gaming market
share and most of the uh beneficial
partners that we are working with we are
looking at opening up other streams of
businesses from each one of these
Partners which we believe there's an
opportunity so we give a reasonably
confident of going the um
the second question that you had in
terms of Group Health piping look at the
end of the day of course it is driven
with pricing and someone could come in
and get very aggressive that is a
possibility but if you go back to the
reason why the Google pricing was uh the
level where it was it was largely a few
large uh you know companies who were
doing it in an aggressive level most of
them today has some solventy channels
challenges and we really don't
anticipate them coming back and doing
the same thing uh you know right now
Capital concern there so we believe that
the market for Google
structurally is getting better
yeah and we believe that this goes
through testing for some more time and
in terms of price increase we took a
price increase as we discussed last year
we had talked about most common we are
taking 15 to 20 price increase on that
base we are able to get for Life
increases not at the same page but we
are still able to get small price
increases and and hold on to the
business the other thing that is
happening in health is that in Q2 we had
talked about the fact that the game the
frequency has got elevated we are seeing
that uh rational guys and and kind of
come down to uh normal levels so from
all of those perspectives we even we
will be concerned about the health
business as of now
thank you for follow-up questions ladies
and Gentlemen please limit your
questions to one for participant should
you have a follow-up question you would
request you to rejoin the question to
you the next question is from the line
of nidesh from investing
please go ahead
thanks for the opportunities
you mentioned that there has been
multiple regulatory drugs and proposed
changes and that could have a disruptive
uh impact on the company on the on the
sector in the short term so canister
elaborate what sort of disruption you
are expecting because of those changes
there will be uh some uh you know
consequent chill uh impact on the ground
right and what we are seeing is a method
of changes happening at the same time so
it's just that uh you know let's look at
couple of things that could create the
amount of disruption one is uh you know
fresh licenses it may not come in by
next year but if that comes in this lot
more Capital coming into this so that
could create some uh competitive
question uh you know that's a
possibility I'm not saying it will
happen but these are things that we you
know you need to be conscious of and
aware of secondly for example commercial
lines there is a talk of complete
detailification if that happens there
could be a round of competition uh you
know we don't believe that it will have
dramatic changes because uh if you look
at the overall
combined ratio of the sector and some of
the players who were very aggressive
last time when this happened they may
not have the capability or the capital
to continue with that approach this time
but still there is always a probability
of amount of deception that's the point
that I want to make but I think the
larger point is that these are all in
our opinion very positive changes from a
longer term perspective and we believe
it should help discipline Underwriters
uh you know players like us who have a
capital brand and presence across
multiple lines of business at scale I
think it should benefit us but you know
we just wanted to kind of tell you that
there is also a probability of some
amount of uh you know distribution given
the amount of changes that are happening
that's always a possibility
sure and then there's a follow-up on
that there is a also talk of
deregulating the commission rate across
all lines of business while expensive
management will be capped at a
particular level so do you see as a
multi-line insurance company we will
have advantage in the retail health
insurance segment because of that that
regulation so I think the advantage for
us is if you look at the proposed uh
expensive management limit that is being
talked about we are within that number
as a company so we are we are
comfortably placed some of the companies
which have been aggressively growing uh
spending a lot of money
we may have to calibrate to that extent
yes there could be an advantage
thank you
we'll take the next question from the
line of maduka Lada from new armor
wealth management please go ahead
oh hi good evening
um most of my questions have been
answered I'll just install a couple of
friends uh one on the motor TV segment
um we're seeing a lot of improvement in
the Lost ratio
so I'm not sure whether you've clarified
this earlier or not
uh but has there been some improvement
taken from uh you know the uh the
restrict the six months or uh
restriction on the period uh of
reporting uh any accident uh so so has
uh what have been the developments on
that and uh you know if you could give
us some guidance in terms of how the
courts are ruling and whether there can
be any uh benefit flowing through uh
more and better we have accounted for
any sort of reserve the leaders because
of that and second on the on on the
group others business which is uh
excluding the employer employee
business uh what is the source of that I
believe they're not doing that business
more with ICT bank so what are the other
what are our other partners uh you know
broadly if you can help us with you know
Banks and BSE some sort of
classification and and against what
products are these attachments
what we've seen happen in there's been a
recent uh Madras high court judgment
which is uh reaffirming this point that
you have to you know find claims within
six months so now we have case law
supporting the change in the regulation
or law of the land which is a positive
what we are beginning to see is some
signs for for first six seven months we
didn't see you will see a big change in
terms of frequency or your acceleration
of planes but as we speak only signs of
some acceleration happening in some
states
uh we will have to study this for some
more time to tell you that it's
happening at the national level but
early signs are positive uh and we will
have to uh if that happens then it could
be a positive for uh for the sector but
as of now we've not taken any benefit of
that in our numbers because it's too
early to take a benefit uh in terms of
your second question uh you know this is
this was always our strength working
with multiple vacation companies uh nvac
HSC is uh we work with uh you know
beautiful uh you know lending companies
we work with a whole host of uh you know
entities which uh you know provide
retail credit with whom we uh sell some
of these uh group other category of
Health Products which is what has come
by which is the point that you were
making that last couple of years let us
know that and we had a relatively higher
share of that business so to that extent
it was negative assessment that has now
come back this year and that's where
this is going from ICC Bank this is on
that account what they previously last
year they stopped selling they haven't
recharged that however what they've done
is uh they have started selling
Indemnity products retail Indian beauty
products both figure branches as also as
attachments for their uh you know
mortgage customers so that's why the
number from the bank side is also
positive
if you look at the percentages we gave
that in the opening remarks
distribution which includes multiple
other Banks so most of the large private
sector Banks we have their Partners most
of the large NBA's and atses we have
their partners and that segment that is
non-is event distribution grew at 44.2
percent
thank you
we'll take the next question from the
line of residual engineer from iafl
institutional equities please go ahead
foreign
yeah
so I just you know wanted some
um you know color on you know how do we
look at the expense ratio of trajectory
right so there are two parts to it over
the past 15 months is the acquisition of
bharti AXA there was one uh you know
trajectory which suggested that you know
the gap between the expense ratios uh
between RPS and us should converge order
you know took two and a half year period
and that is something that will try the
overall combined ratio down on the other
hand uh you know we had this tended to
basically investigate retail health and
digital in order to you know gain some
of those shares uh you know Market
shared there now if I look at uh you
know both these aspects you know it
would be great to just understand one
you know on the Bhatia rationalization
has the progress being slower than
expected and to uh uh you know you'd see
like even on a nine month basis
significant growth in sales expenses or
even overall Opex excluding commissions
but it doesn't seem to reflect that it
is going into retail Health like looking
at the combined ratio of retail as it
seems to be going into motor so just
wanted to understand you know the second
part you know how the expenses are
getting allocated too and as a result uh
what should be the tragedy going for
so is she uh I think uh
your second part of the question with
respect to the progress of the bharti
extra integration in line with what we
have been communicating I think that is
pretty much uh we have kind of realized
whatever Villages that we spoke about I
think the only last energy which we had
said it's something that we will realize
in this financial year is the technology
Synergy consequent to once we get the
applications integrated or merged we
should start realizing the benefit of
the synergic layout from quarter four of
the current year onwards I'm happy to
note that even that particular aspect in
respect of integration between the two
companies are kind of being done and
hence that extent you may start to see
uh the Synergy on the technology cost
play out from Q4 onwards uh to your
first part on with respect to what would
be the trajectory that expenses could
take yes you are right I think there are
multiple aspects that goes into insofar
as determination of the loss Express
ratio trajectory is concerned one is the
function of what kind of Revenue growth
opportunity that one sees uh which is
what I had explained certain lines of
businesses while there are costs that we
kind of continue to incur however the
revenue is something that we have not
been able to completely realize it reach
fullest potential
uh a segment in uh reference is motor
for example clearly we have not been
able to kind of realize the complete
potential of what we would like to see
that segment operated now as and when
let's say the growth comes back that
itself will be a function of let's say
some form of efficiencies or maybe some
form of
uh Improvement that you will get to see
in so far as the expense ratio the
trajectory is concerned the second is
obviously as I mentioned the investments
in retail Health to your other points
was not just a one-off investment it's a
continuing one uh we continue to hire
let's say the number of retail health
agency managers whom as we have
explained will obviously go and add more
number of uh agency distributions so
those costs again comes and it says
today in our p l because it's an actual
number of employees who are getting
onboarded uh in so far as retail Health
the distribution is concerned so which
is why you will you will continue until
the time let's say the benefits in the
form of incremental Revenue playoffs
which is what which is in the past also
which we have explained it roughly takes
about 12 to 18 months for the cycle to
completely get uh efficient is when you
will start seeing let's say incremental
revenues being contributed but in so far
as early signs are concerned I think the
investment seems to be kind of laying
out in line with our expectations and as
to that extent I think we are quite
happy with the way how things are
playing out uh but finally in terms of
what number the expense ratio trajectory
could say I think rather we would look
at it more from a combined issue
perspective which is a combination of
both expense and loss ratios because
different segments includes different
outcomes in terms of the Way businesses
will get sourced there clearly what we
had indicated was over a two-year period
we would want to see a declining slope
on the combined ratio right and we are
pretty much staying on course with
respect to that particular thought
process of ours or I mean already in
line with what we have spoken about for
f523 we had said the combined will stay
range Bound in the 104 levels and in
fy24 you will start seeing a declining
slope we are pretty much on course in
order to kind of uh getting that
reflected and hence that's the
trajectory that one would see in so far
as the combined ratios is concerned
thank you
ladies and gentlemen we'll take that as
a last question I now have the
conference over to Mr bhargav Das Gupta
for closing comments
uh one question I think yeah I think
there was one question which had asked
in the in in the context of how many
agents did we had uh consequent to the
Thousand health agency managers that
number is at about ten thousand agents
is what we have been able to act by
these agencies
so you guys so thank you everyone for uh
for joining the call
it's pretty late for all of you uh look
forward to our interaction during the
quarter thank you thank you so much
thank you
ladies and gentlemen on behalf of
iciclumbar General Insurance Company
Limited that concludes this conference
thank you for joining us and even now
disconnect your lives